<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>The Dragon</name>
		<description>The Dragon Otherworldly Patron from Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything">Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</author>
		<update version="0.0.6">
			<file name="warlock-dragon.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AuroraLegacy/elements/master/supplements/xanathars-guide-to-everything/archetypes/warlock-celestial.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="The Dragon" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_CELESTIAL">
		<supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You've made a pact with a mighty dragon, who has bestowed you with a fraction of its terrifying power. The details of the arrangement varies widely - a metallic dragon may have made the pact to create a force of good or save a life, a chromatic dragon may have made their pact with you in exhange for service... or part of some manipulative plan that the minds of lesser mortals would struggle to comprehend.</p>
			<p class="indent">Most often these bonds are granted by ancient dragons steeped in immense power and knowledge, but sometimes partnerships of the lesser mortals and younger dragons have been recorded in more unique classes </p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_DRACONIC_BLAST" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_ELEMENTAL_DEVASTATION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CELESTIAL_CELESTIAL_RESILIENCE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CELESTIAL_SEARING_VENGEANCE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_DRACONIC_BLAST" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_ELEMENTAL_DEVASTATION" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CELESTIAL_CELESTIAL_RESILIENCE" level="10"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CELESTIAL_SEARING_VENGEANCE" level="14"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
		<supports>Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Dragon lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
			<h5>DRAGON EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>absorb elements, chromatic orb</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>alter self, dragon's breath</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>fear, wind wall</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>4th</td><td><em>fire shield, wall of fire</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>flame strike, greater restoration</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The Celestial lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
			<extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CHROMATIC_ORB</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF</extend>
			<extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_DRAGONS_BREATH</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION</extend>
		</spellcasting>
	</element>

	<element name="Draconic Blast" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_DRACONIC_BLAST">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at first level, you gain the ability to unleash blasts of primal draconic energy from your hand or mouth. You can unleash this power in a 30 foot cone or a 60 foot long, 5 food wide line. Invocations that apply to eldritch blast also apply to Draconic Blast (increases to range apply half as much range to the line form, and one quarter the range of the cone).</p>
			<p class="indent">When you gain this feature, select one damage type of acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison. Creatures in the area of effect must make a Dexterity saving throw, or take 1d10 elemental damage of the selected type. This feature's damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level in Warlock (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use this ability, you can expend a pact magic spell slot to empower the draconic blast, dealing 1d10 additional damage per level of the pact magic slot expended. When empowered, it heals half damage even against creatures that pass their saving throw against it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can unleash a draconic breath in a 30 foot cone or a 60 foot long, 5 food wide line. Affected creatures must make Dexterity saving throw with DC equal to your spell save DC, or take 2d10 damage of your chosen element. When you use this ability, you can expend a pact magic spell slot to empower the draconic blast, dealing 1d10 additional damage per level of the pact magic slot expended. When empowered, it heals half damage even against creatures that pass their saving throw against it.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Elemental Devastation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGON_ELEMENTAL_DEVASTATION">
		<description>
			<p>At 6th level, when you deal the elemental damage type you selected as part of the Dragon blast to a creature, you can inflict an additional elemental ailment baseed on the elemental type. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all uses on a long rest. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>At 6th level, when you deal the elemental damage type you selected as part of the Dragon blast to a creature, you can inflict an additional elemental ailment baseed on the elemental type. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, regaining all uses on a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Celestial Resilience" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_CELESTIAL_CELESTIAL_RESILIENCE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 10th level, you gain temporary hit points whenever you finish a short or long rest. These temporary hit points equal your warlock level + your Charisma modifier. Additionally, choose up to five creatures you can see at the end of the rest. Those creatures each gain temporary hit points equal to half your warlock level + your Charisma modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>After a short or long rest, you gain {{celestial resilience:temp hp}} temporary hit points and you can choose up to five creatures to receive {{celestial resilience:ally temp hp}} temporary hit points each.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="celestial resilience:temp hp" value="level:warlock" />
			<stat name="celestial resilience:temp hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="celestial resilience:ally temp hp" value="level:warlock:half" />
			<stat name="celestial resilience:ally temp hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Searing Vengeance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CELESTIAL_SEARING_VENGEANCE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 14th level, the radiant energy you channel allows you to resist death. When you have to make a death saving throw at the start of your turn, you can instead spring back to your feet with a burst of radiant energy. You regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, and then you stand up if you so choose. Each creature of your choice that is within 30 feet of you takes radiant damage equal to 2d8 + your Charisma modifier, and it is blinded until the end of the current turn. </p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you make a death saving throw at the start of your turn, you can instead regain half of your hit points maximum, stand to your feet if you so choose, and deal 2d8+{{charisma:modifier}} to each creature of your choice within 30 feet, blinding them until the end of your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
